Guide to the Christopher Tunnard Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- PICTORIAL MATERIAL, 1907-1977; Series IV; 1.75 linear feet (7 boxes, 1 folio)
  - Oversize
    - Blueprints
      - House in Jekyl Island, Georgia, undated (Folder 48)
      - House in Tuxedo, New York, undated (Folder 48)
    - Map of Historic Charleston, South Carolina, 1970 (Folder 48)
    - Map of Fairfield Connecticut historic district, undated (Folder 48)
    - UNESCO
      - Kathmandu, Nepal pictorial materials, 1968-1975 (Folder 48)
      - St. Ann, Jamaica area map, 1969 (Folder 48)
- ADDENDUM. WILLIAM EDWARD PARSONS
  Within the Christopher Tunnard papers are papers formerly belonging to William Edward Parsons. He was an alumnus of Yale, having attended from 1895. He became an architect and city planner, and was partner in Bennet, Parsons & Frost, Consulting Architects, of Chicago for 25 years. His work extended from buildings in the Philippines to city plans of Buffalo and Chicago.
  In 1938 Parsons was appointed to the faculty of the Department of Architecture at Yale as the first to make city planning a formal subject of instruction. However he died the next year. His wife gifted the Parsons Medal in 1942 (see box 23, folder 349). Parson was not replaced during WWII, but in 1945 Christopher Tunnard was recruited, and appears to have 'inherited' Parsons's papers, including numerous photographs.
  In their uncatalogued state, the Tunnard papers were contained in 25 boxes, the last two of which were purely Parsons's papers. In their catalogued state the latter have been distributed according to the description below.
  Information in the box column indicates the possible present location of the item.
  - 40 photographs pasted onto stiff card of buildings in Manila. Some dates (1907, 1910, 1913, etc.) and some names (Ambos Camarines, Moncarda, etc.) given. Also notes that some buildings designed by Wm E. Parsons, Consulting Architect, and some notes apparently in his handwriting (eg. # 11). (Box 41, Folder 684)
  - 40 photographs pasted onto stiff card of buildings in Manila. Some dates (1907, 1910, 1913, etc.) and some names (Ambos Camarines, Moncarda, etc.) given. Also notes that some buildings designed by Wm E. Parsons, Consulting Architect, and some notes apparently in his handwriting (eg. # 11) [cont'd]. (Box 42, Folder 689)
  - Photographs of drawings by Bennett, Parsons & Frost. One is of a park at San Juan in Puerto Rico, dated 1925. Others of the 'United States Botanic Gardens'. (Box 45, Folder 718-720)
  - 'The Buffalo City Plan' by Edward H. Bennet and William E. Parsons (Associates H.T. Frost and C. W. Thomas) of Chicago, dated 1921. (Box 46, Folder 721-723)
  - Proposed enlargement of the Capitol Grounds by Bennet, Parsons & Frost. (Box 47, Folder 725-728)
  - City plan of Joliet by Bennet, Parsons & Frost, 1921 [location unknown].
  - A paper of June 1905 by W.E. Parsons on 'The Decorative Value of Sculpture and Architectural Forms in Gardens'. [location unknown]
  - In a folder inscribed 'Town Planning' miscellaneous clippings, notes, photos, mostly 1937 and 1938, and the greater proportion of it from the USA. Also a printed coloured map of New York dated 1857. [location unknown]
  - In a folder inscribed 'Architecture', a letter dated August 23, 1937, from Charles Peterson, Senior Landscape Architect to the US Department of the Interior, to Parsons concerning a scheme for a Museum of American Architecture. Also a copy of a plan by Olmsted's for Union Square, Washington, dated 1934. [location unknown]